<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools" tools:ignore="MissingTranslation">

    <!-- General Strings -->

    <string name="app_name">Salary vs Inflation</string>

    <!-- Menu Items -->

    <string name="action_help">Help</string>
    <string name="action_delete_all">Delete All Entries</string>
    <string name="action_back">Back to List</string>
    
    <!-- UI Strings -->

    <string name="confirm_delete_message">Delete all entered salaries?</string>
    <string name="salary_too_large">Salary too large to process</string>
    <string name="year">Year</string>
    <string name="salary">Salary</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="cpi">CPI</string>
    <string name="raise_cut">Raise/Cut</string>
    <string name="estimated">Estimated</string>
    <string name="get_results">Get Results ></string>
    <string name="delete_salary_entry">Delete Salary Entry</string>
    <string name="salary_list_empty">No salary information submitted</string>
    <string name="add_replace">Add/Replace</string>
    <string name="raise_message">%s RAISE</string>
    <string name="cut_message">%s CUT</string>
    <string name="equal_message">%s</string>
    
    <!-- Colours -->

    <color name="red">#ffff0000</color>
    <color name="green">#ff00ff00</color>
    <color name="blue">#ff0000ff</color>
    
    <!-- Help Text -->

    <string name="help_text">
<![CDATA[
<h1>Introduction</h1>

<p>Over time the value of money decreases, so salaries need to increase proportionately just to maintain their value.
This app allows you to measure your salary against inflation for any period from 1989 to 2013.  Enter figures for just
one year or for many different years, and you can see how inflation has affected your salary, and how it has maintained
(or lost!) its value.</p>

<h1>How We Measure Inflation</h1>

<p>The UK government uses a number of different indices for measuring inflation, the two most important being the
Consumer Price Index (CPI) and the Retail Price Index (RPI).  These take average costs of a vast number of goods and
services, then weight them based on proportionate consumption to produce a figure that represents the increased cost
of living from year to year.  CPI and RPI are similar in many ways, the main differences being that CPI omits the cost
of housing, and that they have different methods of calculating averages.</p>

<p>Since April 2011, CPI is the government\'s preferred index for calculating tax allowances, pension contributions and
the like - this is for a variety of reasons, including reduced volatility and better accuracy.  CPI also tends to report
a slightly lower rate of inflation than RPI, as house prices as of 2014 are currently rising proportionately higher than
the prices of other goods and services.</p>

<p>As CPI is the officially-preferred index, we use this to calculate the effect of inflation on your salary, but please
remember that this is just one possible measure of inflation.</p>

<p>CPI data is calculated monthly and describes the rise in the cost of living since the same month the previous year.
Monthly figures are averaged to form both quarterly and yearly figures, but for simplicity, we just use the
yearly-average figures.</p>

<h1>Entering Your Salary Information</h1>

<p>Simply select a year from the drop-down, then enter your (yearly) salary into the box and press Add/Replace.  For
your convenience, the app will automatically pre-select the following year ready for your next figure.</p>

<p>If you make a mistake with a figure, just re-enter it -  the new figure will override the old.</p>

<p>Tap the trash can icon against any figure to delete it, or tap the trash can in the top menu bar to remove all
figures.</p>

<p>This app will remember all entered salary data between runs, so please delete your salary data once you\'re happy
that you don\'t want it remembered any more, to keep it from prying eyes!</p>

<h1>Interpreting the results</h1>

<p>The results show how your salary has fared against inflation from the first salary you entered up to the most
recently available CPI data.</p>

<p>Where you have provided a salary, you will find an estimate based on your salary for the previous year, plus an
indication of whether your salary has increased in real terms, or decreased.  Where you have not provided a salary,
only the estimate is shown.  Note that during gaps in your record, your salary is assumed to rise in line with
inflation, so you may see a big adjustment at the end of such a gap, which would in reality be spread out over the
entire period - the solution, of course, is to provide more data!  The more data you provide, the more accurate the
calculations will become.</p>

<p>In theory, your salary should increase over the rate of inflation whenever your company has seen fit to reward you
for your efforts, and should increase in line with inflation at all other times.  In practice, in a depressed economy
it\'s common to see salaries decrease with respect to inflation.</p>

<h1>We Will Not Share Your Data!</h1>

<p>Please note that this app does not request permissions to perform any kind of network communication, and is therefore
incapable of transmitting your salary information off of your device.</p>

<p>Your data is stored on the device for the purpose of calculating your results and is remembered between runs to avoid
you having to re-enter it each time - but you can delete all or part of this data at any time by tapping the trash can
next to any data you wish to remove.</p>

<p>(For the extra paranoid, note that you can also go into the settings for your device, navigate to Manage
Applications, select this app in the list and tap "Clear Data" to remove all information that it has stored.  We assert
that this is not required - the delete functions mentioned above will also delete your entered salary data - but fully
support your right to not have to take our word for it!)</p>
]]>
    </string>

</resources>